Yes, sir.
You guys good?
Yeah, good to see everybody.
Appreciate you sticking around.
Late here. Um I just uh obviously, you
know, we're just one one pick today.
Uh took uh Army Mason Thomas with the
second round pick 40
uh defensive end out of Oklahoma.
Uh
a really really talented rusher. Um you
know, 2-year starter
that I mean he's 6'2 240 245 run 465.
Um a guy that uh we love his get-off,
his speed around the edge. Um he's a
relentless high-motor kid.
Um [snorts]
he's got sneaky power.
And he plays the run, too. So, this is a
kid that we actually we we um
noticed him in '24. You know, you're
watching they had a couple defensive
players in on that, you know, that team
and
you're like, "Who's this 32 that keeps
popping?" Um and then you watch him in
the summer, you watch him throughout the
year. Just a guy that we had on our
radar um dating back to '24. So,
really excited to add him to the mix.
So, with that I'll I'll open up to you
guys. Mike, it seems like all three of
your defensive players have a lot of
speed. I mean, what was
>> [clears throat]
>> emphasis in in trying to get faster?
Yeah, I think uh Sam, I think it was it
was adding speed throughout the defense,
not only up front um at each level.
Um you know, you got a 4-3-8 corner, you
got a D-tackle that moves really well,
and you got a a speed rusher. So, I
think all three of those guys infusing
that speed um that energy, that um
explosiveness. I think that's that was
uh big-time target for us. How much How
much of having a speed rusher was
something that you guys wanted to sort
of accomplish during this draft? And is
that a reflection based on just
trying to have a more diversified
pass-rushing group?
Yeah, I think I think you're right. I
think we I mean, as we I think we've
we've kind of missed that element, you
know, with that group. So, having a guy
that can run off the ball, you know, get
tackles and turn quick, and um I think
that opens up guys the inside to, you
know, clean things up. So, um I think
that this guy has a true speed rusher
that I don't think he's a one-trick
pony, either. I think he actually does
have some power, he can counter. Um but
I think that just that that helps the
entire group, cuz you want to have some
versatility within within those guys.
Mike, [snorts] you had mentioned his
physical attributes, 6'2 241
>> [clears throat]
>> 242 lbs.
How much of an emphasis are you guys
going to place on him to potentially put
on some weight, or are y'all comfortable
with that tweener type size? You know,
he he's you know, in his career I think
it's been a steady progression. I mean,
he was he was a 200-lb kid, you know, at
the freshman year. I think he's
progressively, you know, added the
weight.
He [snorts] I think 245 is a good weight
for him. I think he can put on more
weight, but you don't want to sacrifice
the speed, explosion, the quickness just
to add a, you know, a few more pounds.
And I think he's he's in a good spot
where, you know, like I said, I think
the kid he he can play the run. I think
he's he lacks ideal length and size, but
he will strike blocks. He he can get
off. He You know, he plays really hard.
So, I think he's not just a
a rusher. Mike, I was wondering about
your perspective on the two first-round
picks, just what you liked from
Yeah, so I mean, with uh
with Delaine, uh you know, a guy that
another guy we watched watching him at
'24 Virginia Tech. Just
>> [snorts]
>> the versatility, the athleticism, uh the
sticky coverage. Uh like I said, ability
to play inside and outside.
He's got really good feet, really good
hips. He tackles.
He uh I think the one question I think
people had was, "How fast was he?" And
then he, you know, runs 4-3-8. So, he's
answered every question we had. You
know, we we zoomed like we you know, V
said we we zoomed him last week, crushed
it.
>> [snorts]
>> Uh I think he's just the sky's the limit
for him.
And then Peter,
just a a versatile guy, you know, nose
tackle. I think he can play nose, he can
play D-tackle.
Uh really athletic, heavy-handed.
I think he's he's got a really good
upside. I mean, he's 21 years old. So, I
think he's played uh he's played in
different schemes. I think he's [snorts]
a prototype 3-tech, but again, I think
he can also play nose. So, those guys
are explosive um ascending players. And
Mike, we all know Spags has a type at
defensive end or has the length. What
makes this a better fit for his
[clears throat] defense and what you
guys want to do? I think just the way he
plays. I think he's he's tough. I think
he he plays the run. He doesn't run
around blocks. He's not afraid to to get
in a 6-technique and and play double
teams. So, he's not just a guy that's
going to just just seek sacks. So, I
think the way he plays the game,
uh I think the character piece obviously
matters, too. I think that he's a he is
[snorts] a all-out relentless high-motor
kid that um I know he's not prototype.
It's it's not typically what Spags has
uh uh you know, these guys have played
for Spags, but I think [snorts] the
combination of his skill and the
character make you feel good about it. A
couple years ago, Mike, you you you
brought in Josh Uche, who's kind of a
similar size and everything. Yep.
>> Anything learned in that experience that
helped inform this decision?
[snorts and clears throat] I think it it
makes it a little easier when you when
you get them now, where it's, you know,
midseason. It is it's a little tricky
just to to fit guys in. And you're so
caught up in the in-season. So, I think
now getting him where we got him, having
[snorts] a full off-season, getting, you
know, him him into the defense, you have
you have time. So, I think um
>> [snorts]
>> I think that I think that is probably
the biggest difference. Is there like
any convincing with Spags knowing that
there's a type that he likes, or was he
like
No, no, he was actually all in with this
kid. I think, you know, I I forgot to
mention we have DeMarco Murray on staff
who was at Oklahoma. And that was with
him. So,
and DeMarco's been great, and he raves
about the kid. So, having a coach that
was with him every single day, and you
know, put his stamp on him, it made
Spags
um much more confident. So, Yeah, on
Delaine, you said you he he popped for
you guys at Virginia Tech. But when he
made the move to LSU and the year he
had,
>> Yeah. what does that prove to you
uh with a guy moving up to I guess the
SEC? It means more, all that kind of
>> Yeah, I think it just shows how I mean,
we talking to the kids today, you can
feel his competitiveness, how his uh
he's he's got a a really good confident
way about him. And I think you saw it on
the first tape against Clemson when he
was at LSU, he had the pick. Just
you watched we watched the tape again
last week. Like there's really
>> [snorts]
>> even a lot of these corners, I mean,
they have bad plays, they give up
touchdowns and stuff. He was very
consistent throughout the year. I
thought he was as a consistent cover guy
as as as we've done in the last, you
know, 5-10 years. Um but it seemed like
he just stepped up to each challenge um
each week. You guys have played defense
today. What's your outlook for day
three?
Yeah, I think there's some pockets. I
mean, there's, you know, I think we
always we we followed the board. And I
think there's it's not going to be a
"Hey, we have to go to this position. We
have to go to this position." Just cuz
we drafted you know, maybe we go heavy
defense, but
>> [snorts]
>> I think there are some skill guys, there
are some receivers, there are some
runners. I think there's a couple
offensive linemen, but there's also some
corners. And um so, I think, you know,
picking early in the fourth we'll we'll
have a good opportunity. All right,
we're going to go around the room. Go
ahead, Matt. After you made the pick
[snorts] at 40, like what was the rest
of the night for you? You got
[clears throat] 16 more picks in the
draft.
Were you dead set against not jumping
back in, or was there any consideration?
No, I mean, throughout the you're
fielding calls from from teams, seeing
if you want to come up. And um listen,
there were there were a few guys that
started to fall that you make some calls
and say, "Hey, does this make sense?"
And if they fall to a certain point,
maybe let's go get him. But once those
guys went, um probably in the mid-third,
we kind of pivoted. And we saw there was
a lot of good players on the board. And
picking early in four, I thought we, you
know, we'll get one of the guys that um
that we like. Todd, Mike
Red talked yesterday about the
predictive models and all the stuff you
guys did and kind of how the thing works
out. This is
evolving every year. Generally speaking,
like the further down the draft you get,
how [clears throat] how accurate have
the models been? What what are you guys
learning as you go on that? Yeah, it's
it's it's I think it helps really in the
first couple rounds, cuz I think
everyone kind of sees the the players
somewhat similar in terms of just the
top 40, top 50. Once you get into the
fourth, fifth round, it you kind of
throw some of that out the window, just
cuz there's so many so many variables to
to these guys getting picked. And
everyone's boards look different. But um
[snorts] like V said, with the with the
first round and second round, it's been
extremely um productive for us. Um and
and and accurate. Um so, I'll give I'll
give Mark Richards and our our team a
ton of credit, cuz it's been a great
resource um you know, for us. Mike, just
your point about that your board and how
this has played out. How much would you
have anticipated going in that it would
be three defensive players in in these
top 40 picks? I don't think so. I think
we I think just that, you know, how how
it fell. I really do. I mean, these
these three guys were were guys that we
talked about a ton, you know, since
since, you know, September, October.
>> [snorts]
>> And um
to to to think we would have gotten
these three guys, I'm I'm I'm quite
surprised, uh to be honest. Um
But it wasn't [snorts] one of the things
where, "Hey, we need a corner. We need a
D-tackle. We need an edge." Like, you
know, there were some other needs that
we have and and still have. Um but but
in those three cases, those were just
opportunities that were too good to pass
up. Last one, Sam. Last one for Sam. Oh,
you're good. Push it. I got it. Yeah, go
ahead. And Mike, I wanted to ask about
Army Mason one thing. Had a big game
against Auburn. Yeah. Sacked him in the
end. But I just wanted to know what you
see [clears throat] from him in that
potential. And also, uh you guys on
third downs last year had some
difficulties on his game as a closer.
Yeah. I just wanted to know what what
you thought from him, and then if that
was a need because of that. Yeah, I
think that game I think there were some
other games that you were those are
that's that that is who he is. I think
that's um
I think the the the cool thing about him
was I the Tennessee game where he does
the quad, you know, he has a fum- fumble
recovery, he goes scores a touchdown.
It's it's a bad quad injury. I mean, he
was out I think he was out a few games.
And then he comes [snorts] back, plays
against Alabama, does really well, but
it's those snaps in the fourth quarter
where he's just he's, you know, he's
gassing up. He's coming off the ball and
>> [snorts]
>> he's a guy that can create turnovers
both with his speed. I think his motor.
>> [snorts]
>> I think just having that guy
a threat to win consistently will help
everybody from from George to Chris, you
know, all the the whole group. So, I
think it's it's a big addition.
Okay, thanks, Mike. Thanks, Mike.
Thanks, Mike. Thank you, guys.
Appreciate it.